Being the adventures of a young man whose principal
interests are rape, ultra-violence and Beethoven.
A Clockwork Orange is a science fiction, crime film directed by Stanley Kubrick.
In a near-future Britain, young Alexander DeLarge and his pals get
their kicks beating and raping anyone they please.
When not destroying the lives of others, Alex swoons to the music of Beethoven.
The state, eager to crack down on juvenile crime, gives an incarcerated Alex the option
to undergo an invasive procedure that'll rob him of all personal agency.
In a time when conscience is a commodity, can Alex change his tune?
Alex, played by Malcolm McDowell.
Mr. Alexander, played by Patrick Magee.
Dr. Brodsky, played by Carl Duering.
Chief Guard, played by Michael Bates.
Dim, played by Warren Clarke.
Georgie, played by James Marcus.
A Clockwork Orange is a 1971 dystopian crime film written,
produced, and directed by Stanley Kubrick.
It is based on Anthony Burgess's 1962 novel.
The film employs disturbing and violent themes to comment on psychiatry, juvenile delinquency, youth
gangs, and broader social, political, and economic issues in a dystopian near-future Britain.
Alex (Malcolm McDowell), the central character, is a charismatic, anti-social delinquent whose interests include
classical music (especially that of Beethoven), committing rape, theft, and "ultra-violence".
He leads a small gang of thugs, Pete (Michael Tarn), Georgie (James Marcus), and Dim (Warren Clarke),
whom he calls his droogs (from the Russian word друг, which is "friend", "buddy").
The film chronicles the horrific crime spree of his gang, his capture, and attempted rehabilitation via an experimental
psychological conditioning technique (the "Ludovico Technique") promoted by the Minister of the Interior (Anthony Sharp).
Alex narrates most of the film in Nadsat, a fractured adolescent slang composed of
Slavic languages (especially Russian), English, and Cockney rhyming slang.
The film premiered in New York City on 19 December 1971 and was
released in the United Kingdom on 13 January 1972.
The film was met with polarised reviews from critics and was
controversial due to its depictions of graphic violence.
After it was cited as having inspired copycat acts of violence, the film was withdrawn from
British cinemas at Kubrick's behest, and it was also banned in several other countries.
In the years following, the film underwent a critical
re-evaluation and earned a cult following.
It received several awards and nominations, with four nominations
at the 44th Academy Awards, including Best Picture.
In the British Film Institute's 2012 Sight & Sound polls of the world's greatest films, A
Clockwork Orange was ranked 75th in the directors' poll and 235th in the critics' poll.
In 2020, the film was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the
Library of Congress as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
The film explores themes of london, england, robbery, street
gang, great britain, based on novel or book.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking and intense.